<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<chapter id="preference" revisionflag="added">
  <title>JBoss Web Services and the development environment</title> 
  <para>
    In this chapter you will learn how to change preferences and set the default server runtime.
  </para>
   
  <section id="jbosswspreference">
    <title>Preferences</title> 
    <para>
      In this section you will know how JBoss Web Services preferences can be modified during the development process.
    </para>
     
    <para>
	To navigate to the preferences page click on <menuchoice>
		<guimenuitem>Window</guimenuitem>
		<guimenuitem>Preferences</guimenuitem>
		<guimenuitem>JBoss Tools</guimenuitem>
		<guimenuitem>Web Services</guimenuitem>
		<guimenuitem>JBossWS Preferences</guimenuitem>
        </menuchoice>
    </para>
     
    <para>
		On this page you can manage the JBoss Web Services Runtime. Use the appropriate buttons to <guibutton>Add</guibutton> more runtimes or to <property>Remove</property> those that are not needed.
    </para>
     
    <figure>
      <title>JBossWS Preferences Page</title> 
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/preference/Jbossws_preference.png"/>
        </imageobject>
      </mediaobject>
    </figure>
     
    <para>
		Clicking on the <guibutton>Add</guibutton> or <guibutton>Edit</guibutton> button will open the form where you can configure a new JBossWS runtime and change the JBossWS runtime path and modify the name and version of the existing JBossWS runtime settings. Click <guibutton>Finish</guibutton> to apply the changes.
    </para>
     
    <figure>
      <title>Edit JBossWS Runtime</title> 
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/preference/Jbossws_preference_new.png"/>
        </imageobject>
      </mediaobject>
    </figure>
     
    <para>
	WS container allows Source and Javadoc locations to be set via the Properties dialog on each contained JAR: right-click on any JAR file in the Project Explorer view, select <guibutton>Properties</guibutton>. Choose <guibutton>Java Source Attachment</guibutton> and select the location (folder, JAR or ZIP) containing new source for the chosen JAR using one of the suggested options (workspace, external folder or file), or enter the path manually.
    </para>
     
    <figure>
      <title>Classpath Container: Java Source Attachment</title> 
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/preference/jbossws_container1.png"/>
        </imageobject>
      </mediaobject>
    </figure>
     
    <para>
		Click on <guibutton>Apply</guibutton> and then on <guibutton>OK</guibutton>.
    </para>
     
    <para>
	To change the Javadoc location choose <guibutton>Javadoc Location</guibutton> and specify URL to the documentation generated by Javadoc. The Javadoc location will contain a file called <guibutton>package-list</guibutton>.
    </para>
     
    <figure>
      <title>Classpath Container: Javadoc Location</title> 
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/preference/jbossws_container2.png"/>
        </imageobject>
      </mediaobject>
    </figure>
     
    <para>
	Click on <guibutton>Apply</guibutton> and then <guibutton>OK</guibutton>.
    </para>
  </section>
   
  <section id="serverruntime">
    <title>Default Server and Runtime</title> 
    <para>
      Open <menuchoice><guimenuitem>Window</guimenuitem><guimenuitem>Preferences</guimenuitem><guimenuitem>Web Services</guimenuitem><guimenuitem>Server and Runtime</guimenuitem></menuchoice>. On this page, you can specify a default server and runtime.
    </para>
	<note>
    	<para>
			For ease of use, set the runtime to JBoss WS.
		</para>
	</note>
    <para>
		After the server and runtime are specified, click on the <guibutton>Apply</guibutton> button to save the values.
    </para>
     
    <figure>
      <title>Specifying a default server and runtime</title> 
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/preference/jbossws_server_runtime.png"/>
        </imageobject>
      </mediaobject>
    </figure>
  </section>
</chapter>
