<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<chapter id="overview">
   <title>JBossWS Runtime Overview</title>

    <para>JBossWS is a web service framework developed as a part of the JBoss Application Server. It implements the JAX-WS specification that defines a programming model and run-time architecture for implementing web services in Java, targeted at the Java Platform, Enterprise Edition 5 (Java EE 5).</para>
    <para>JBossWS integrates with most current JBoss Application Server releases as well as earlier ones, that did implement the J2EE 1.4 specifications. Even though JAX-RPC, the web service specification for J2EE 1.4, is still supported JBossWS does put a clear focus on JAX-WS.</para>

<section>
    <title>Key Features of JBossWS</title>
    <para>For a start, we propose you to look through the table of main features of JBossWS Runtime:</para>

    <table>
        
        <title>Key Functionality for JBossWS</title>
        <tgroup cols="2">
            
            <colspec colnum="1" align="left" colwidth="2*"/>
            <colspec colnum="2" colwidth="4*"/>
           
            
            <thead>
                <row>
                    <entry>Feature</entry>
                    <entry>Benefit</entry>
                  
                </row>
            </thead>
            
            <tbody>
                
                <row>
                    <entry><para>JAX-RPC and JAX-WS support</para></entry>
                    <entry><para>JBossWS implements both the JAX-WS and JAX-RPC specifications.</para></entry>
                   
                </row>
                
                <row>
                    <entry><para>EJB 2.1, EJB3 and JSE endpoints</para></entry>
                    <entry><para>JBossWS supports EJB 2.1, EJB3 and JSE as Web Service Endpoints.</para></entry>
                    
                </row>
                
                <row>
                    <entry><para>WS-Security 1.0 for XML Encryption/Signature of the SOAP message</para></entry>
                    <entry><para>WS-Security standardizes authorization, encryption, and digital signature processing of web services.</para></entry>
                    
                </row>
                
                <row>
                    <entry><para>JBoss AS</para></entry>
                    <entry><para>JBoss Application Server 5 (JavaEE 5 compliant) web service stack.</para></entry>
                    
                </row>
                
                <row>
                    <entry><para>Support for MTOM/XOP and SwA-Ref</para></entry>
                    <entry><para>Message Transmission Optimization Mechanism (MTOM) and XML-binary Optimized Packaging (XOP) more efficiently serialize XML Infosets that have certain types of content.</para></entry>
                    
                </row>
                
            </tbody>
            
        </tgroup>
    </table>
    
    
</section>
<section>
        <title>Other relevant resources on the topic</title>

        <para>You can find some extra information on:</para>
        <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    <ulink url="http://www.jboss.org/community/wiki/JBossWS-FAQ#Tools">JBossWS Tools Wiki FAQ.</ulink>
                </para>
            </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>

        
    </section>

    
    

</chapter>